# **ABOUT ME**

I am a combat Veteran turned Dev Nerd.

# **Projects**

2019 Revirr.com - Revirr is here to help with the process by offering true entry level professional positions as well as a guide to show what you may qualify for based on degree, experience, skills and interests.

Powered by: Wordpress

2019 ChalkingCode.com - Learn how to code from front end to backend.

Powered by: Github

# CONTACT



978 Radcliffe Rd



Towson, Md 301-996-4681



skylarbarrowman@gmail.com

# **INTERESTS**

Coding

My Dog

Binge watching Netflix

Sports

Coffee

# Skylar Barrowman

#### WEB DEVELOPER

# CAREER OBJECTIVE

To be able to work for an encouraging company that will assist me in developing, improving, and obtaining the necessary skills in order to become the best engineer possible.

# **EDUCATION**

#### FreeCodeCamp

Full Stack Development

#### The Odin Project

Front End development

#### **W3C Schools**

Front and back end dev

# TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:

JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, HTML5, CSS, CSS3, Web Programming Skills, E-Commerce, Teamwork, Verbal Communication, cross-browser compatibility, Web User Interface Design (UI), Security Principles, Object-Oriented Design, Web Services (REST/SOAP), Multimedia Content Development, API's

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Platform Ops/Platform Specialist

2017 to present | Zerofox

- Baltimore, Md

 $\label{thm:contributor} Key contributor to startup company's fast evolution from manually doing work to automating the small things.$ 

- Created and maintained Foxscripts (Java) to appropriately identify harmful social media content.
- Spearheaded and published research regarding security on social media networks. Mentioned by Wired, Huffington Post, CNN and many other popular sources.
- $\bullet \text{Award the Unsung Hero Award for significant transformative contributions in support of Zerofox's mission. } \\$
- Automated the health check system by utilizing API's increasing efficiency by 75%
- Analyzed the inefficiencies and pain points of current workflow and built a series of python scripts.

# MILITARY EXPERIENCE

# **USMC Infantry Team Leader**

2011–2015 Operation enduring Freedom 2013 Afghanistan

# **Army Reserves**

2015–2017 343<sup>rd</sup> medical co ground ambulance

2017-Present 450<sup>th</sup> Civil affairs batt (airborne)

# **EXPERTISE**

CMS Customizations and plugin development

Widget development

Framework knowledge

Gimp/Photoshop

Global Project Management

# SKILLS

Attentive listening and effective oral communication skills

Great at Problem Solving

Good Leadership Skills

Critical Thinker

Ability to quickly create and apply ideas and solutions